<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Alex blog</title>
  <subtitle>The start of the blog</subtitle>
  <link href="https://alex-yi37.github.io/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://alex-yi37.github.io/" />
  <updated>2026-01-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://alex-yi37.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Alex Yi</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Recording my &quot;Designing Data Intensive Applications&quot; read through</title>
    <link href="https://alex-yi37.github.io/blog/ddia-read-through-first-post/" />
    <updated>2026-01-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://alex-yi37.github.io/blog/ddia-read-through-first-post/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For a while now, I&#39;ve been trying to read through &amp;quot;Designing Data Intensive Applications, 1st Edition&amp;quot; (DDIA for short) by Martin Kleppmann in an attempt to become more familiar with distributed systems and maybe have a better time with system design interviews, though that&#39;s more of a secondary benefit. I&#39;m mostly just interested in the topic and really don&#39;t see much of a way to get actual experience with distributed systems stuff outside of directly working on one (probably unlikely in the short term). For a little background, I&#39;ve been a software developer for around three years, mainly doing front end work with React and its various frameworks with a smattering of back end api work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting back to the book, I think I first tried reading it in 2023 and got to maybe the sixth or seventh chapter. As I am prone to doing, I eventually bounced off of it for whatever reason. Coming back to the book in late 2025, I tried skimming the chapter that I think I left off on and didn&#39;t really understand much of it. I decided to re-read from the beginning to refresh my memory and maybe pick up on some things I may have missed my first read through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This re-read has also coincided with wanting to start blogging, so it seemed natural to kick off the posts with trying to record what I learn this time. Unfortunately, I&#39;ve been doing my re-read for a few months now but only started blogging in January 2026 so the beginning of the book isn&#39;t so fresh in my mind at the moment. I guess this is just a good reason to review earlier chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>